

# LUIS RICARDO CAYETANO HERRERA

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

#### PRESENTATION

3321477155

richych92@gmail.com



https://about.me/richy\_92

Guadalajara, Jal.



I consider myself a person with values, hard-working, observant, dynamic, with a particular interest in analysis and web application development. I like to think of the idea of turning a problem into a solution using IT. Young accustomed to individual and collaborative work, my experience has taught me to work under pressure and overcoming these in different circumstances.

My goal is to be part of a competitive company where I can develop professionally, contribute my knowledge to the projects assigned to me and always contribute to the continuous improvement and success of the organization. I am a loyal and committed person with the company that gives me the opportunity to be part of your team.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### 08/2019 - Currently

- ASP.NET MVC
- **C**#
- ✓ SQL Server
- Angular
- ✓ Bootstrap
- HTML
- ✓ Entity framework
- **NodeJS**
- **✓** Express
- MySQL
- ✓ Javascript
- API

#### 04/2019 - 04/2020

- ASP.NET (MVC,Web Forms, Web API)
- **C**#
- **SOL Server**
- Azure DevOps
- Git
- **JOuerv**
- **Booststrap CSS**
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ Entity framework
- LINQ
- ✓ SAP GUI Scripting
- IIS
- SSIS
- Kendo UI
- **Javascript**
- PowerShell
- **API Rest**
- **VBA**

# **♥** Full Stack Developer

#### **FREELANCE**

- Provide my services as an analyst and developer to clients who have software projects.
- Estimating the time and cost in software projects.
- Changes in designs and functionality in already developed web applications.
- Design and define the architecture of web applications.
- Propose software solutions according to customer needs.
- Deployment applications on IIS and nginx servers.
- Adapt to the way of working defined by the client.
- Working with GIT as a source code management tool.
- Write the documentation required by the client.
- Design and model of API's with the Swagger tool.

### Business Systems Analyst

## **JABIL**

- Collaborate with Developers, DBAs, BSA and Application Administrators from different areas in order to follow the same development standards.
- Developing and implementing shop floor and technology solutions.
- Design and create database, stored procedure with SQL Server 2014 y 2016.
- Work with MockingBot as a collaborative prototyping tool to create product
- Establish and maintain excellent collaboration and relationships with the different area supervisors to streamline internal processes and with the client.
- Process improvement and problem-solving skills (Lean Six Sigma).
- Work with end users to determine business needs/requirements for new/enhanced systems or applications.
- Perform analysis to provide optimizations and process automation in order to reduce time and costs to the organization.
- Work shoulder to shoulder with materials SME team to create software products.
- Migrate applications from other sites to our and adapt it to our needs.
- Responsible for the operation and administration of IIS web servers and SQL Server across Staging and Production environments.
- Deploy web applications to IIS and SSIS packages to SQL Server.

- Work with the SAP team to support users (access and roles) and automate processes in SAP through SAP GUI Scripting.
- Implement ETL (extract, transform, and load) processes with SSIS (SQL Server Integration Services).
- Schedule job for sending automated reports.
- Provide technical support in the Service Now platform to internal users (warehouse, materials, MRO, shop floor systems, traffic and logistics).
- Write technical documentation of implemented software projects.
- Manage Source Code Control Systems (Azure DevOps and GIT).
- I developed an application web that involves the manufacturing process (with MES via database) since the entry and exit of materials in shop floor to entry and exit of materials from warehouse (with SAP via Visual Basic Script) and build dashboards as a key element to make the right decisions.
- Ability to write scripts using win batch, Visual Basic Script language, PowerShell and excels macros to automate tedious tasks.

#### 05/2016 - 03/2019

- ✓ ASP.NET (MVC, Windows Forms)
- ✓ SQL Server
- ✓ Angular 2 +
- ✓ **JQuery**
- ✓ Bootstrap CSS
- ✓ SVN, TFS & GIT
- **✓** Entity Framework
- ✓ Telerik
- ✓ MvSOL
- ✓ Kendo UI
- ✓ Php Laravel
- ✓ Node JS
- ✓ Express JS
- ✓ Sequelize ORM
- ✓ Angular JS
- ✓ MongoDB
- ✓ API Rest
- ✓ Swagger
- ✓ WSO2(API Manager & Identity Server)

# Web Developer

#### **BIOXOR**

- Work with multidisciplinary teams and fulfill each of the projects in a timely manner and with a focus on the client.
- Design and create database with SQL Server and MySQL.
- Work on a goal-driven basis and show good result.
- Perform analysis of functional and non-functional requirements.
- Manage different tools for version control (SVN, Microsoft Team Foundation Server and GIT).
- Software development effort estimation.
- Following coding standards and source code documentation provided by org.
- Offer the support service for internal applications and with the client.
- Design and documentation of API's with the Swagger tool.
- Creation of web services API REST.
- Add new features and make changes to existing applications.
- Create end user and technical manuals.
- Work under the agile SCRUM methodology and agile practices with CMMI-DEV level III goals.
- Design, develop, test and deploy web application.
- As a Full Stack developer I contributed to several software projects from scratch such as desktop applications, web applications and API Rest: for example, development of SPA applications with Angular, consumption and integration of own and third-party APIs such as Google Maps, Instagram and Twitter.

#### 02/2016 - 05/2016

- ✓ Bootstrap CSS
- **✓** JQuery
- ✓ GIT
- ✓ MySQL
- ✓ Php
- ✓ Node JS
- ✓ Express JS
- ✓ Angular JS
- ✓ MongoDB

#### Web Developer (Freelance)

#### WIZCHIMP

- Work under pressure, good at working to deadlines, able to follow the startup culture.
- Hard working with good time management and multitasking skills.
- Use open source technologies that offer fast and scalable application development.
- Develop API Rest web services.
- Design and model SQL and Non-SQL databases.
- Implement the Conekta API to make online payments.

08/2015 - 01/2016

- ✓ ASP.NET MVC
- ✓ C#
- ✓ SQL Server
- ✓ SVN
- ✓ **JQuery**
- ✓ Bootstrap CSS
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ Crystal Reports
- ✓ Clarion
- ✓ LINQ

#### • Programmer Analyst

QUANTUM

- Requirements analysis for the migration of a desktop poultry system to a web environment.
- Work with the technical lead to define the application stack, structure, architecture and design patterns to implement in the projects.
- Work with Crystal Reports as tool to generate reports.
- Provide support for a desktop ERP application adding new features and making changes.
- Implement the interface from a desktop application to a web application using SPA (Single-page Application).

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2010 - 02/2016

Bachelor's degree in System Enginner

Specializing in application development with web technologies
Tecnológico Nacional de México/Instituto Tecnológico de Oaxaca.
Professional license: 11423914

07/15/2019 -07/17/2019 (24 hours)

**COMPETITION / COURSES** 

Azure Bootcamp. by Microsoft.

Jabil Green Poin, t Site 7, Guadalajara, Jal.

10/2017 (34 hours of content)

Angular: From scratch to expert
Online course by udemy.com

06/2017 (45 hours of content) ASP.NET MVC C#

Online course by pluralsight.com

11/2014 (48 hours) Hackathon by Digital Festival 2014.

Secretaría de Administración del Gobierno del Estado de Oaxaca **Proposal:** I participated in the project "Let's take care of our environment", my team and me developed a API REST and mobile app.

04/04/2014 -04/06/2014 (48 hours) Hackathon OAHACKA - ¡CATAPULTA! 2014

**Proposal**: I participated in the project "Help us find missing people" my team and me developed a wep app, the idea was to make easier and faster the government procedures "Amber Alert".

### Mobile Programming Course

11/2012 (16 hours) At Instituto Tecnológico de Oaxaca, during the X Academic Day of the degree in computer science and computer systems. Take a mobile programming course (Android).

#### **MY NETWORKS**

# VII IVEI WORK









#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native

English: Level B1 (At Linguatec)